What's up, John Jordan?
Well, we got so much to talk about tonight.
Trump makes an Irish exit from Canada.
I had to DC to crash the most tremendous birthday
bash in American history.
And the author, James Patterson,
will be here along with his co-author, Bill Clinton tonight.
OK?
So, let's get into the headline.
Now, this is supposed to be study of broad week for Trump.
And things started out oh, so well.
He arrived at the G7 competently,
strolling out of the woods like a contestant
on the Golden Bachelorette, or a shaved sassquatch, you know?
You see what you want to see.
Now, this is an important G7 for Trump,
because he had to prove that he had the discipline
and wherewithal to fix the global economy after he
f**ked up the global economy.
And you know what?
He almost nailed it.
We all know the great prime minister of the UK,
and we just signed a document.
Mrs. Swap, I thought about that.
You went very poor at documents.
You didn't win the anti-acquiring.
Don't worry, don't worry.
There's a five-second rule with trade agreements.
Trump's still totally good to eat those documents.
And I know some of you haters are going to make fun of them,
but Trump didn't drop the papers by accident.
It was a 4D chess move to check out
the British prime ministers, but don't get dumped.
But before Trump could sign and or drop any other trade deals,
he decided to peace out.
Overnight, President Trump with an abrupt about face,
announcing he's cutting short his trip
to the G7 summit in Canada,
racing back to the White House instead.
I have to be back very important.
I want to just thank our great-nose.
But you're probably seeing what I see.
And I have to be back.
We all know what this is, right?
You're at an event.
You have to rush home because something came up.
Look, I get it.
None of us like to poop in an unfamiliar place.
Sometimes when you have a big matchup coming up,
you just need that home-field advantage.
I understand, Donald.
But of course, the real reason Donald Trump rushed home
to Washington was to deal with the war between Israel and Iran.
And the big question was, was he rushing home
to help negotiate an end to the war
or to bring America into the war?
It's the most important decision a nation can make.
And one, that we've whiffed on for the last 10, 20, 30, 40.
It doesn't matter. The point is,
it'd be really reassuring to know that the president
has a clear and consistent plan.
So Mr. President, are you looking for war or ceasefire?
What about looking for a ceasefire?
And say I was looking for a ceasefire.
Oh, shit. OK.
He's not looking for a ceasefire.
We're looking at better than ceasefire.
Oh, great.
Yeah. Better than a ceasefire.
ceasefire plus.
That's great.
I hate watching ads.
That's wonderful.
This is good news.
I'm glad you're going to negotiate with Iran.
I don't know. I'm not too much in a book to negotiate.
OK. All right.
Not in the mood. OK.
The president's not vibrant on negotiations then.
So it's war.
Because who wouldn't negotiate besides you, Mr. President?
He's considering sending the vice president
to negotiate with the Iranians.
I think this is fantastic.
JD Vance is a great choice to negotiate.
The Iranians will agree to anything to get him the f*** out of there.
You know what?
And it's great for peace.
Because if Trump is negotiating, it sounds like we're not
going to flatten Tehran anytime soon.
The president warned everyone in Iran's capital city to flee.
Posting everyone should immediately evacuate to Iran
with no additional explanation.
You know what? I could use some additional explanation.
Mr. President, I am more confused than ever.
Please just sum up your explanation in one clean tweet.
President Trump has just posted new comments directed at Iran.
We know exactly where the so-called Supreme Leader is hiding.
He is an easy target, but is safe there.
We are not going to take him out and then in parentheses,
kill at least not for now.
OK.
So we know where the Iatola is, but he's safe.
We could kill him, but we won't.
For now, maybe later.
We'll find out next on the Golden Bachelorette, OK?
How does one tweet and have six different positions?
I mean, clearly, we're not going to get any clarity
from listening to President Trump.
Maybe other people in his inner circle
can shed some light on America's position.
Tucker Carlson, huge supporter of the president.
What do you think of the war?
I just don't want my country to be further weakened or destroyed
by another one of these wars.
And boy, if you can't connect the dots after 25 years,
the ****.
You're either too dumb to participate in the conversation
or you're just a liar who doesn't care.
Wow.
I mean, Tucker, he hasn't been mistrustraught
since the WNBA got popular.
OK, Mr. President, I hope you understand
what Tucker Carlson is saying.
I don't know what Tucker Carlson is saying.
Let him go get a television network and say it so that people listen.
Thank you.
Oh, snap.
Trump's like, go on TV and say it, you bitch.
That's right.
You can't because you got kicked off Fox News
for lying about me winning the 2020 election,
which I appreciate, you bitch.
So yes, Trump is not on the same page as Tucker.
And he seems to be at odds with some of the other top magamines as well.
The American people have been brainwashed into believing
that America has to engage in these foreign wars
in order for us to survive.
And it's absolutely not true.
Oh my God.
I can't believe I'm a green with marjorie Taylor Greene.
I'm not war with myself.
And this can't be right.
Keep playing the clip.
I'm sure I'll find something to disagree with her on.
They don't want to hear about politics.
They want to be able to afford food,
and they want to be able to afford gas.
And they just want to have fun for once in their life.
They want to have fun.
Yes, I still agree with her for once in their life.
Americans just want to have fun.
I don't want to war.
I want to dance.
Although you know what, I'm pretty sure Americans do know
how to have fun regardless of international conflicts.
I've never gotten a text saying, hey, bro,
territorial dispute in the South China Sea,
barbecue's canceled.
So, doesn't seem like Trump is listening
to the anti-war wing of his party.
Maybe he'll listen to the anti-war wing of his own administration,
like Tulsi Gabbard, his own director of national intelligence.
Tulsi Gabbard testified at March that the intelligence community said
Iran wasn't building a nuclear weapon.
What she said, I think they were very close to having that weapon.
LAUGHTER
This is the benefit of appointing unqualified, crazy people to your team.
You could always be like, do you know how crazy ununqualified she is?
I don't care what she said.
So, Trump is beefing with the anti-war wing of his party
and dismissing intelligence from his own cabinet,
showing that Iran is not actually building nukes.
It certainly seems to be leaning in a Let's Do a World War III direction.
Weirdly enough, the final confirmation might be pizza.
According to an account on X called the Pentagon Pizza Report,
nearly all pizza establishments nearby the Pentagon
have experienced a huge surge in activity.
Here's why when U.S. military personnel face a national emergency,
they work late into the night and can't leave their desks.
At 8.57 p.m. Thursday, the Pentagon Pizza Report reported
that the closest and second closest dominoes to the Pentagon
had surged in traffic.
Oh, my God, we're going to war!
Or everyone at the Pentagon just got divorced at the same time!
Look, I don't know how things are going to end,
but it seems like they're trending in a bad direction.
I will say this, though.
If you told me after election day that within four months of Trump's presidency,
I'd be staring at a dominoes pizza tracker
to figure out if we're going to enter the final war of mankind.
I'd have said, that's about right.
For more on the pending war with Iran, we go live outside the Pentagon
with our own Michael Kosta.
Michael!
CHEERING AND APPLAUSE
Michael.
I'm curious, Michael.
What is the latest?
Jordan, this is a nuanced and complicated situation
and the only solution is for America to enter a decades-long total war with Iran.
Make no mistake.
The U.S. military needs to dig in, buckle down,
pick up some Mikey K's meatlovers pizzas with extra tangy sauce
and prepare for the worst.
I'm sorry.
What was that last part you said about preparing for the worst?
Yes.
We'll probably need a new draft, too.
Millions of able-bodied young men ready to fight for America
and chow down on Mikey K's buffalo chicken supreme mam-mamiya
with a free 45-ounce Mountain Dew Code red, just like Nona used to make.
LAUGHTER
What, do you own a pizza parlor?
Are you trying to profiteer from a war?
No, no, no.
I have a small investment in a pizza place nearby
that I also manage and busboy at,
but that in no way affects my impartial analysis.
I've looked at the evidence and we have to go to war against Iran.
Possibly Iraq again and definitely India.
LAUGHTER
What did India do?
Well, they're a regional superpower, Jordan.
They're a threat to our survival.
Right now, their military leaders are plotting against us working day and night,
ordering delicious taker.
Michael, do you have a pizza place in India?
Absolutely not.
It's a small, tandoori kitchen called second to non.
LAUGHTER
Free mango lassi with every any order, just like Nona used to make.
Hey, Costa, come on, man. That's, this is crazy.
I know. With any order, Jordan, there is no minimum.
No, no, what's crazy is you're trying to start World War III
so you can, what, sell bad takeout?
Bad takeout.
How dare you?
Art Chutney is the talk of New Delhi.
I assume I can't figure out what they're saying.
But, what's the big deal?
Defense contractors can go to our nation
into endless pointless wars for profit,
but Nona, Costa, can't get a taste?
Look, you're all bad.
Americans don't want war.
Isn't there a way to make money off peace
so the world can live in harmony?
International relations aren't that simple, Jordan.
Two nations, their total opposites can't overcome
their cultural differences,
uniting in a perfect blend of magical serenity.
The only place that that exists
is in our new delicious sushi taco.
LAUGHTER
As my Nona used to say,
mmm, as we, Konichiwa.
Oh, yeah, we get out of here.
Michael Costa, everyone.
MUSIC