Welcome one and all to the late show.
I'm your host, Stephen Colbert.
This will go.
Oh, my God.
You can check your calendars on me here.
This weekend was the official start of summer,
as my audience knows all too well.
Thank you.
Thank you, you brave souls, for waiting outside
and the humidity that the Weather Channel has described
as the Devil's Trouser Chili.
What else is going on?
Oh, right.
We're at war in the Middle East again.
At least it sure looks that way.
Yeah.
And it happened a lot sooner than anyone thought.
See, last week, Trump's press secretary said this.
I have a message directly from the president, and I quote,
based on the fact that there's a substantial chance
of negotiations that may or may not take place
with Iran in the near future.
I will make my decision whether or not
to go within the next two weeks.
That would have been perfect for me,
because we would have been on vacation next week,
and I wouldn't have known any of this was happening.
Now I'm going to have to cancel my reservation
that Samples Fordo.
But on Saturday, or just Saturday,
or just Saturday, and Saturday, Trump surprised the world,
announcing that the U.S. launch strikes
on three Iranian nuclear facilities.
Now, were we facing an imminent threat?
I don't know.
On one hand, Iran's slogan isn't life to America.
But it's hard to trust Donald Trump
to be the one making these kinds of decisions.
It kind of feels like we're all in the backseat
while the Uber driver goes on a road rage.
Hey, hey, hey, buddy, we're in the car, too.
Okay?
And if we're dead, we can't give you five stars.
That's my...
That is my heart rule for rating drivers.
I'm dead.
No.
Arrivalive?
I'm giving five.
Trump addressed the nation for a couple of minutes
later on Saturday night, and wrapped it up
in just the weirdest way.
I want to just thank everybody, and in particular,
God, I want to just say, we love you, God,
and we love our great military, protect them.
Okay, it's a nice sentiment, you know?
But a weird way to say it.
Yes, I have always been a devout believer in God.
We love you, God.
I know.
We haven't always been on the greatest terms
since I made the deal with a guy with a polkae head
and the Flamenhoes.
But point is, you rock, big guy.
Stay in school.
Have a great summer, Namaste.
Namaste.
After the bombs were dropped on Sunday,
Trump posted this message with a key misspelling.
The great B-2 pilots have just landed safely in Missouri.
Thank you for a job.
Well done.
Donucked, J-Trump.
President of the United States.
Yes.
Okay.
Donucked.
J-Trump, spoken like a man who got Donucked in Denog.
We're learning more about the actual bombing, the attack plan.
It's codename Operation Midnight Hammer.
And no, it's not porn.
LAUGHTER
Yet.
Here's what happened.
In order to avoid detection, the plan was carried out
by seven B-2 stealth bombers.
And I'm... Is this true?
I'm told we have a picture of the stealth planes.
Wow.
Yeah.
They are good.
The planes were carrying 30,000-pound bombs
known as bunker busters, officially called mobs,
or massive ordinance penetrators.
The most...
The most phallic-sounding weapon since the...
Tomahawk cruise shunts.
So America spies must have truly compelling intelligence,
indicating that Iran was close to building a nuclear weapon,
or... or not, because America spies that Iran wasn't
building a nuclear weapon.
Okay.
Hold on.
Are they sure?
Maybe our top spies just didn't have time to do a thorough check
because they were too busy hanging off of a biplane.
LAUGHTER
But if the intelligence wasn't there, how did Trump decide
it was time to attack Iran's nuclear program?
Well, according to a senior administration official,
it was based on a feeling...
LAUGHTER
The president had.
CHEERING
If you are making a decision that could endanger the lives
of American troops and civilians, help me out.
Legal scholars, what does that require?
MUSIC
Thank you.
Hey, Mayor. Thank you.
Hey, Mayor.
And thank you.
CHEERING
Thank you for your service.
Thank you for that staff.
And remember, this is an America's first military industrial rodeo.
I've been making jokes about whether or not we should be going
to war in the Middle East for 22 years.
I did jokes from the Middle East for the service people
who were sent into harm's way based on no credible intelligence.
But I will say this.
I will say this, sure.
I will say this about the Bush administration.
At least they respected us enough to lie to us.
Apparently, the Trump administration does not give a damn
what we think.
They're not presenting any evidence.
Just come on, guys.
Just at least scare us a little.
I missed the days when Colin Powell went to the UN Security Council
and passionately waved a tube of country-time lemonade powder.
I mean, just that much, just that much of the powder
could have refreshed everyone in that building.
I mean, Trump should be out there telling us
that Iran is hiding 50 tons of mustard gas on a turkey farm
or 50 tons of mustard turkey on a gas farm
or human animal hybrids or anything.
Just sell it with sizzle.
This is just lazy.
It's got low production values.
Imagine if the next Transformers movie was just like,
you know what?
I think we're just going to state cars in this one.
What?
Put some effort in.
I'm mad.
This isn't me, mad.
What's going to happen next?
Whatever happens next, you know they're going to make
JD Vance go on TV and embarrass himself.
Because here's what he said on Sunday to sell this war
that is definitely not a war.
Is the United States now at war with Iran?
No, we're not at war with Iran.
John, we're at war with Iran's nuclear program.
Nope, nope.
That's not how it works.
Honey, I'm not cheating on you with Stacey.
I'm cheating on you with parts of Stacey.
Very selective.
And yes.
And yes, we do call it Operation Midnight Hammer.
Then.
Pretty easy.
Okay.
Then JD Sauntered Over to Press the Meet with Kristen Welker.
What do you say to members of Congress who say it was
unconstitutional for the president to act unilaterally?
First of all, the president has clear authority to act
to prevent the proliferation of weapons of mass destruction.
And the worst weapon of mass destruction of them all is nuclear.
Debatable.
From my money, the worst weapon of mass destruction
is the Taco Bell Triple Lupa.
If this all feels like deja vu, Vance promises this time is different.
I certainly empathize with Americans who are exhausted after 25 years
of foreign entanglements in the Middle East.
But the difference is that back then we had dumb presidents.
Yes.
Back then.
He's got a point.
Back then we had dumb presidents.
And now we have Donak J. Trump.
He is smart.
You'll remember back in 2003, the US winner of Iraq
with the specific goal of toppling Saddam Hussein.
This time, Vance promises that's not the idea.
Does the United States support Israel killing Iran's leader?
Yes.
Well, look, that's up to the Israelis.
But our view has been very clear that we don't want a regime change.
Okay.
Great.
Loud and very clear and immediately contradicted by the president,
who posted,
it's not politely correct to use the term regime change.
Mega.
Mega, your whole damn thing is America first.
You can't just hand other countries your slogan.
That's like if McDonald's had an ad campaign that said,
I'm loving it, it being Burger King.
No.
I'm mad.
God, bless it.
I'm sorry you had to see it.
Let it out.
Today, a Ron launched missiles against two U.S. bases,
including one in Qatar, but both Qatar and the Trump administration
were made aware of the Iranian attack ahead of time.