Welcome, one and all, to the late show.
I'm your host, Stephen Colbert.
This week on...
CHEERING AND APPLAUSE
You can check your calendars on me here.
This weekend was the official start of summer,
as my audience knows all too well.
CHEERING AND APPLAUSE
Thank you.
Thank you, you brave souls, for waiting outside
in the humidity that the weather channel has described
as the Devil's Trouser Chili.
LAUGHTER
What else is going on?
What else is going?
Oh, right.
We're at war in the Middle East again.
At least it sure looks that way.
CHEERING AND APPLAUSE
Yeah.
And it happened a lot sooner than anyone thought.
See, last week, Trump's press secretary said this.
I have a message directly from the president, and I quote,
based on the fact that there's a substantial chance
of negotiations that may or may not take place
with Iran in the near future.
I will make my decision whether or not to go
within the next two weeks.
That would have been perfect.
For me, because we would have been on vacation next week,
and I wouldn't have known any of this was happening.
Now I'm going to have to cancel my reservation
that samples Fordo.
LAUGHTER
But on Saturday, or just Saturday,
or there's just Saturday, and Saturday, Trump's surprised
the world, announcing that the US launched strikes
on three Iranian nuclear facilities.
Now, were we facing an imminent threat?
I don't know.
On one hand, Iran's slogan isn't life to America.
But it's hard to trust Donald Trump to be the one making
these kinds of decisions.
It kind of feels like we're all in the backseat
while the Uber driver goes on a road rage.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, buddy, we're in the car, too, OK?
And if we're dead, we can't give you five stars.
That's my...
That is my heart rule for rating drivers.
I'm dead.
No.
Arrival live?
I'm giving five.
Trump addressed the nation for a couple of minutes
later on Saturday night, and wrapped it up in just the weirdest way.
I want to just thank everybody, and in particular,
God, I want to just say, we love you God,
and we love our great military, protect them.
OK, it's a nice sentiment, you know,
but a weird way to say it.
Yes, I have always been a devout believer in God.
We love you God.
I know we haven't always been on the greatest terms
since I made the deal with a guy with a polkae
in the Flamengoves.
But point is, you rock, big guy.
Stay in school.
Have a great summer, Namaste.
LAUGHTER
Namaste.
After the bombs were dropped on Sunday,
Trump posted this message with a key misspelling.
The great B-2 pilots have just landed safely in Missouri.
Thank you for a job.
Well done.
Donucked J. Trump, president of the United States.
Yes.
OK.
Yeah.
Yes.
Donucked J. Trump, spoken like a man who got Donucked in Denoggan.
We're learning more about the actual bombing, the attack plan.
It's codename Operation Midnight Hammer.
And no, it's not porn.
LAUGHTER
Yet.
Here's what happened.
In order to avoid detection, the plan was carried out
by seven B-2 stealth bombers.
And I'm, is this true?
I'm told we have a picture of the stealth planes.
Wow.
They are good.
The planes were carrying 30,000-pound bombs
known as bunker busters, officially called Mops
or massive ordinance penetrators.
The most, most phallic sounding weapons
since the Tomahawk cruise trance.
So America spies must have truly compelling intelligence,
indicating that Iran was close to building a nuclear weapon
or not, because America spies that Iran wasn't
building a nuclear weapon.
OK.
Hold on.
Are they sure?
Maybe our top spies just didn't have time to do a thorough check
because they were too busy hanging off of a biplane.
But if the intelligence wasn't there,
how did Trump decide it was time to attack Iran's nuclear
program?
Well, according to a senior administration official,
it was based on a feeling the president had.
If you are making a decision that could
endanger the lives of American troops and civilians,
help me out.
Legal scholars, what does that require?
Thank you.
Hey, Mayor.
Thank you for your service.
And thank you for that staff.
And remember, this is an America's first military industrial
rodeo.
I've been making jokes about whether or not
we should be going to war in the Middle East for 22 years.
I did jokes from the Middle East for the service people
who were sent into harm's way based on no credible intelligence.
But I will say this.
I will say this.
Sure, sure.
I will say this about the Bush administration.
At least they respected us enough to lie to us.
Apparently, the Trump administration does not give a damn
what we think.
They're not presenting any evidence.
Just come on, guys.
Just at least scare us a little.
I missed the days when Colin Powell went to the UN Security
Council and passionately waved a tube of country time
lemonade powder.
I mean, just that much, just that much of the powder
could have refreshed everyone in that building.
Trump should be out there telling us
that Iran is hiding 50 tons of mustard gas on a turkey farm,
or 50 tons of mustard turkey on a gas farm,
or human animal hybrids, or anything.
Just sell it with sizzle.
This is just lazy.
It's got low production value.
As imagine, if the next Transformers movie was just like,
you know what?
I think we're just going to state cars in this one.
Put some effort in.
I know.
No, I'm mad.
This isn't me, mad.
What's going to happen next?
Whatever happens next, you know they're
going to make JD Vance go on TV and embarrass himself.
Because here's what he said on Sunday
to sell this war that is definitely not a war.
Is the United States now at war with Iran?
No, we're not at war with Iran.
John, we're at war with Iran's nuclear program.
Nope, nope.
That's not how it works.
Honey, I'm not cheating on you with Stacey.
I'm cheating on you with parts of Stacey.
Very selective.
CHEERING AND APPLAUSE
And yes.
And yes, we do call it Operation Midnight Hammer.
Then...
Pretty.
OK.
Then JD Sauntered Over To Press the Meat with Kristen Welker.
What do you say to members of Congress
who say it was unconstitutional for the president
to act unilaterally?
First of all, the president has clear authority
to act to prevent the proliferation of weapons
of mass destruction.
And the worst weapon of mass destruction of them all
is nuclear.
Debatable.
From my money, the worst weapon of mass destruction
is the Taco Bell Triple Lupa.
LAUGHTER
If this all feels like deja vu,
Vance promises, this time is different.
I certainly empathize with Americans who are exhausted
after 25 years of foreign entanglements in the Middle East.
But the difference is that back then,
we had dumb presidents.
Yes.
Back then...
He's got a point.
Back then, we had dumb presidents.
And now we have Donak J. Trump.
LAUGHTER
CHEERING AND APPLAUSE
And the other guy...
Thank you, guys.
That was very nice.
CHEERING AND APPLAUSE
He...
He is smart.
LAUGHTER
You'll remember back in 2003, the US-Winter to Iraq
with the specific goal of toppling Saddam Hussein.
This time, Vance promises.
That's not the idea.
Does the United States support Israel killing Iran's leader?
Well, look, that's up to the Israelis,
but our view has been very clear that we don't want a regime change.
OK, great, loud and very clear
and immediately contradicted by the president, who posted,
it's not politically correct to use the term regime change.
But if the current Iranian regime is unable to make Iran great again...
Why wouldn't there be a regime change?
Miga.
LAUGHTER
Miga?
What?
Miga, your whole damn thing is America first.
You can't just hand other countries your slogan.
That's like if McDonald's had an ad campaign that said,
I'm loving it, it being Burger King.
LAUGHTER
No.
I'm mad.
God, bless it.
CHEERING AND APPLAUSE
Sorry, you had to see it.
What's that thing?
Let it out, let it out.
Today, Iran launched missiles against two U.S. bases,
including one in Qatar, but both Qatar and the Trump administration
were made aware of the Iranian attack ahead of time.
And so thankfully, no casualties were reported.
Hopefully, that'll be the end.
But who knows?
Because immediately after the strikes on Saturday,
Iran warned there would be everlasting consequences.
Everlasting consequences.
Also, the slogan of Taco Bell's Triple Lupa.
We got a great show tonight.
My guests are Jesus Elba and U.S.E. Merrill Carries,
Zoran Mamdani and Brad Land.
When we come back, I'll tell you more about that race.
It's minutes.
CHEERING AND APPLAUSE